Lucas Fern

Lifeguard, Coding Instructor, and Data Science Student at the University of Melbourne



East St Kilda, 3183, Australia



(+61) 0431 621 232



lucaslfern@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/lucas-fern



github.com/lucas-fern

Skills

- Planning
- Problem Solving
- Leadership
- Public Speaking
- Programming
 - o Python
- o HTML
- o Java
- o CSS/Sass
- o R
- o SQL
- o MATLAB
- Mathematics
 - Statistics
 - Probability
- Typesetting (LaTeX)

Certifications

Working with Children Check (Valid to 26/02/2024)

HLTAID003

Provide First Aid (06/2018-06/2021)

HLTAID007

Provide advanced resuscitation (06/2018-06/2021)

PUAOPE0100C

Operate an AED in an emergency (06/2018-06/2021)

PROFILE

An independent student with a passion for problem solving and a focus on academic performance. Studying Data Science at the University of Melbourne. Proficient at programming in a range of languages; especially Python and Java.

Proven record of strong communication, public-speaking, and leadership skills from a background in teaching and customer service.

Over 8 years of combined volunteering experience with Surf Lifesaving Australia and at the University of Melbourne.

Enthusiastic about continuously learning and developing new skills.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science – Data Science 01/2019 – Present The University of Melbourne Weighted Average Mark: 85.29 Areas of Study:

- Probability / Statistics
- Computer Science
- Software Modelling and Design
- Machine Learning
- Artificial Intelligence
- Economics / Game Theory

High School Albert Park College ATAR: 95.25

02/2013 - 10/2018

12/2020 - Present

WORK EXPERIENCE

Programming / Robotics Instructor
Junior Engineers

Junior Engineers delivers educational programs in coding and robotics for primary and junior high school kids aged 7-15.

Responsibilities:

- Instructing holiday programs, and weekly after-school programs at multiple schools in the Melbourne suburbs of Brighton and Elwood.
- Teaching introductory Python, JavaScript and Arduino programming, as well as essential basic computer science skills.
- Using tools such as Scratch and Minecraft Education edition with its integrated code execution to help students enjoy learning.

Achievements:

- Increased enrolment in taught classes by more than 80% after first 3 sessions.
- Developed an energetic and engaging teaching style to further students' existing passions for programming and robotics.

WORK EXPERIENCE (continued)

Developer / Chief Technology Officer BoozeBet

12/2020 - Present

BoozeBet is a start-up company in the alcohol delivery industry; allowing users to enter raffles where winners receive an alcohol of their choice delivered to their door.

- Worked with the previous overseas developer to transfer ownership of code and publish a
 development version of the product.
- Refactored, optimised, and enforced consistent style for the entire Laravel codebase.
- Developed a style guide and overhauled the website design to follow defined stylistic guidelines.
- Configured the MySQL database on the production server and migrated existing data.

Lifeguard 10/2017 – Present

Melbourne Sports and Aquatic Centre (MSAC)

Achievements:

- Developed strong professional communication skills with both colleagues and patrons, especially with conflict management in high-pressure situations.
- Participated in MSAC's Platinum Pool Certification, demonstrating highest standards in aquatic safety and risk management.
- Gained abundant practice working with and managing large groups of lifeguards during Australia's largest swimming events.
- Refined ability for public speaking through a considerable amount of front facing customer service experience.

Mathematics Tutor 2018 – 2019

Tutored senior year students from multiple families at Albert Park College in VCE Maths Methods.

Achievements:

 Formally recognised in graduating year for an ability to teach in an exceptionally engaging and productive way.

VOLUNTEERING EXPERIENCE

Lifesaver 09/2012 - Present

Port Melbourne / Anglesea Life Saving Club

Achievements:

- Completed over 400 hours of unpaid volunteer work with Life Saving Victoria, comprised of beach patrols as well as substantial First Aid and rescue training at Port Melbourne, St Kilda, and Anglesea Life Saving Clubs.
- Significant experience in remaining professional while managing First Aid emergencies and deescalating aggressive conflicts.

Science Student Ambassador

01/2020 - Present

The University of Melbourne

Student ambassadors work closely with the Faculty of Science to deliver events for current and prospective students.

Responsibilities:

• Presenting as a panellist in multiple webinars over 2020, including the University open day, and with the School of Computing and Information Systems (CIS) for high school students in India.

Achievements:

- Presented to over 450 students at the CIS India webinar.
- Attended professional development sessions focused on Public Speaking and Leadership skills.

Lucas Fern